VIVUDH PRASHAR

438 988 7172 | <u>prasharvivudh1994@gmail.com</u> Montréal, QC H4B2X9

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vivudh-prashar-2a04a789/

https://github.com/vprasha27?tab=repositories

Professional Summary

Enthusiastic engineering graduate holding part-time work experience in Vosker as a Technical Support Agent. Possess hands-on experience in Automation Testing of academic projects. Meticulous and detail- oriented with excellent observational, organizational and communication skills. Ambitious Student Intern with skills in Data Analysis and Entrepreneurship. Strong passion for Electronics and software industry and committed to forging new paths to contribute to company objectives.

Technical Skills

Languages: Java, Scala, Python (Basics), HTML, CSS, JavaScript (Ajax, NodeJS), Selenium (Junit, TestNG), React

Database: MySQL, Firebase

Statistics/Machine Learning: Data Analysis /Visualization and Storytelling, Big Data

Tools: Tableau, Power BI, Alteryx, WordPress, Jupiter Notebook

Methodology: Agile, JIRA(Basics)

Client Handling: Customer Interaction, Innovation, Entrepreneurship

Education

Post Graduation Diploma in Computer Technology and Software Testing Expected in June 2022

Institution: Cegep De Gaspesie Et Des Iles | Montreal Quebec

Currently Pursuing

Advanced Professional Diploma in Big Data and Entrepreneurship July 2018

Institution: Concordia University | Montreal, QC

GPA: 3.649

Bachelor's Degree in Electronics and Communications Engineering April 2017

Institution: Beant College of Engineering and Technology | Punjab, India

GPA: 1.67

Professional Experience

Technical Support Representative Company: Vosker | Montreal, QC

Aug 2020 – Mar 2022

Provided on-call and in chat support for camera issues related to spy point

Technical Support Representative

Company: Gexel Telecom | Montreal, QC

- Assisted customers with more difficult technical issues requiring a greater level of personalized care and in greater length.
- Assisted interlocutors in the process of repairing a software or hardware failure.
- Handled the Social Media Support

Technical Support Representative

Aug 2017 - Sept 2017

Company: Revclerx Pvt Ltd | Chandigarh, India

Provided IT support for the US based company MindMatrix

Academic Projects

Real Estate Project (Disciple Assistance):

- Built the business logic of the application using JavaScript, AJAX and NodeJS
- Leveraged MySQL and phpMyAdmin for database designing
- Developed end-to-end automation framework using Selenium and executed Suite using Junit

Ecommerce Project (Cosmo Styles):

- Developed Project using HTML CSS JAVASCRIPT and phpMyAdmin and MySQL queries for data retrieval.
- Used Nodejs and ajax for APIs
- Accessed JIRA for logging Stories and Bugs
- Performed manual and automated regression tests for reduction of errors in the application

Carsharing Project (Zolocar):

- Performed Full Stack Development of the application
- Created accessible, responsive, functional user interfaces of the web application using HTML CSS JavaScript
- Used Firebase for secure authentication
- Developed Technical Documentation of Project

Payroll for (First Aid):

- Performed Full Stack Development of the application
- Created accessible, responsive, functional user interfaces of the web application using HTML CSS
 JavaScript and firebase as its backend

Certifications

- Linux Overview and Installation
- React.js (LinkedIn Certification)
- Software Testing: Tools (LinkedIn Certification)
- Python (Skill Badge on LinkedIn)

Languages Known

- English (Fluent)
- French (Spoken-Intermediate)

Dec 2019- Aug 2020